Curriculum Vitae of Erhan Yaşar

Personal Information

Turkish 13.07.1985

+90 533 494 0 400 mail@erhanyasar.com.tr erhanyasar.com.tr Moda, Istanbul / Turkey



Desired Position

Senior/Lead/Principal Frontend Architect

Summary

After graduating as a Computer Engineer Navy Ensign upon completing Naval High School and Naval Academy respectively, I served 6.5 years on various assignments as a TR Navy Officer both domestically and under command of NATO and UN. Soon after started master, I shifted my career into research, design, and development of UX & Frontend, whilst literally retiring from Army. Besides being happy to be involved in any phases amongst product to IT infrastructure, feel much more comforted when focusing on architectural interface and cognitive experience behind it in regards to assure end-to-end service quality.

Work Experience

Sep 2021 - Current - Bilişim Education Center

| Sep 2021 - Current

Instructor

Jan 2020 - Current - Testimonial Tree

Jun 2021 - Current

- Devtagon - eSystems

| Aug 2020- Mar 2021 | Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Jul 2014 - Oct 2018

Frontend Developer

Senior Frontend Developer

- Related Digital Oct 2017 - Oct 2018 - Arete Consulting - erhanyasar.com.tr

| Jun 2016 - Jun 2017 | Jul 2014 - Jun 2016

Sep 2007 - Dec 2013

Navy Officer @ Turkish Naval Forces

- North Task Group Command Headquarter's Officer | Mar 2013 - Dec 2013 - TCG KEMALREIS (F-247) Anti-Submarine Warfare Officer | Jul 2011 - Mar 2013 - TCG YILDIRIM (F-243) Underwater Weapons Officer | Jun 2008 - Jul 2011 - Intern Officer | Sep 2007 - Jun 2008

Education

2013 - 2020

Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University

MSc | Computational Art & Design BEng | Computer Engineering

2003 - 2007 Naval Academy 2003 - 2007 **Naval Academy**

BSc | Naval Science

Skills & Competences

- Turkish (Native), English (Advanced, IELTS 6.5 Overall Academic), French (Intermediate)
- Oceangoing Watchkeeping Officer / Yatch Captain & 2* CMAS diver
- Leading up to 200+ people, 5 years of sea service, 14+ years of Naval Forces experience
- Multilingual operability within stressful & multicultural environments like UN & NATO
- A/A1/A2/B/B1/D1/F/M class driver's license

Appreciations & **Publications**

- Fleet C.O. & TCG YILDIRIM (F-243) C.O. Appreciations 3 times in total
- Measuring Cognitive Friction on Mobile E-Commerce Applications

Work Conditions

- Full-time & Remote Preferably, Contractor | Employed
- Visa required in case of relocation

References

- Hakan Aysel, Founder of Devtagon
- Murat Bilgin, Retired Marine Colonel, Turkish Naval Forces
- Salih Ofluoğlu, Prof.Dr., Chief of Enformatics at Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University